Fearless lives forever.
Bohemian Rhapsody is a music, drama film directed by Bryan Singer.
Singer Freddie Mercury, guitarist Brian May, drummer Roger Taylor and bass guitarist John Deacon
take the music world by storm when they form the rock 'n' roll band Queen in 1970.
Hit songs become instant classics.
When Mercury's increasingly wild lifestyle starts to spiral out of control, Queen soon faces its
greatest challenge yet – finding a way to keep the band together amid the success and excess.
Freddie Mercury, played by Rami Malek.
Brian May, played by Gwilym Lee.
Roger Taylor, played by Ben Hardy.
John Deacon, played by Joseph Mazzello.
Mary Austin, played by Lucy Boynton.
John Reid, played by Aidan Gillen.
Bohemian Rhapsody is a 2018 biographical drama film that focuses on the life of Freddie Mercury, the lead singer of the British rock
band Queen, from the formation of the band in 1970 to their 1985 Live Aid performance at the original Wembley Stadium.
It was directed by Bryan Singer from a screenplay by Anthony McCarten,
and produced by Graham King and Queen manager Jim Beach.
It stars Rami Malek as Mercury, with Lucy Boynton, Gwilym Lee, Ben Hardy, Joe Mazzello,
Aidan Gillen, Allen Leech, Tom Hollander, and Mike Myers in supporting roles.
Queen members Brian May and Roger Taylor also served as consultants.
A British-American venture, it was produced by 20th Century Fox, Regency
Enterprises, GK Films and Queen Films, and was distributed by Fox.
The film was announced in late 2010, with Sacha Baron Cohen set to play Mercury.
After he left the project in mid-2013 following creative differences with
producers, the project languished until Malek was cast in November 2016.
Singer served as director through most of principal photography, which began in London in September 2017,
but was fired in December 2017 due to frequent absences and clashes with the cast and crew.
Dexter Fletcher, who was originally set to direct when the project was early in development, was hired to complete the film; Singer
retained sole director credit as per Directors Guild of America guidelines, while Fletcher received an executive producer credit.
Filming concluded in January 2018.
Bohemian Rhapsody premiered at the Wembley Arena on October 23, 2018, and was theatrically released in
the United Kingdom the next day and in the United States on 2 November, to mixed reviews.
While the musical sequences and Malek's performance were particularly praised, Singer's direction, the film's
portrayal of Mercury and other personnel, and its use of creative licence were criticized.
However, it was well received by audiences and became a major box office success, grossing over $910.8 million worldwide on a production budget of $50–55
million, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2018 worldwide and setting the all-time box office records for the biographical and drama genres.
Bohemian Rhapsody received numerous accolades, including a leading four wins at the 91st Academy Awards for Best Actor
(Malek), Best Film Editing, Best Sound Editing and Best Sound Mixing; it was also nominated for Best Picture.
The film also won Best Motion Picture – Drama at the 76th Golden Globe Awards, and was nominated for the Producers Guild of America Award for Best
Theatrical Motion Picture and BAFTA Award for Best British Film, while Malek won the Golden Globe, Screen Actors Guild and BAFTA for Best Actor.
The film explores themes of london, england, aids, musician, 1970s, biography.
The tone is emotional.